[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐]
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
We've covered a lot of ground already,
我们已经讨论了一些基础知识，
so today I want to review and reinforce concepts.
所以今天我要回顾并强化概念。
To do that, we'll explore two things.
为此，我们要进行两项探索
First, we'll code up a basic pipeline
首先，我们会编码一个基本管道
for supervised learning.
进行监督学习。
I'll show you how multiple classifiers
我会向大家展示多个分类器
can solve the same problem.
如何解决同一个问题。
Next, we'll build up a little more intuition
然后，我们要锐化直觉
for what it means for an algorithm to learn something
关于一个算法从数据中学习的真正含义，
from data, because that sounds kind of magical, but it's not.
因为尽管听起来这很魔幻，实际上一点也不
To kick things off, let's look at a common experiment
为了扫平障碍，我们来看一个常见的
you might want to do.
你可能想要进行的实验
Imagine you're building a spam classifier.
想象你在建立一个垃圾邮件分类器。
That's just a function that labels an incoming email
这仅仅是一个功能， 把刚收到的邮件标记为
as spam or not spam.
垃圾邮件或正常邮件。
Now, say you've already collected a data set
现在，你已经收集了一些数据，
and you're ready to train a model.
这已经为训练一个模型做好准备。
But before you put it into production,
但在使用它之前，
there's a question you need to answer first--
首先需要回答一个问题：
how accurate will it be when you use it to classify emails that
这个模型究竟可以做到多准确
weren't in your training data?
如果用它来分类你的数据中没有的邮件。
As best we can, we want to verify our models work well
我们希望尽可能地确认模型工作正常，
before we deploy them.
在使用它之前。
And we can do an experiment to help us figure that out.
我们可以通过一个实验来帮助检验这一点。
One approach is to partition our data set into two parts.
一个办法是把已有的数据分成两部分。
We'll call these Train and Test.
我们称之为训练数据和测试数据。
We'll use Train to train our model
我们用训练数据来训练我们的模型，
and Test to see how accurate it is on new data.
使用测试数据 来测试模型在新数据上运行的准确度。
That's a common pattern, so let's see how it looks in code.
这是一个常见的模式， 让我们来看看怎么用代码实现。
To kick things off, let's import a data set into [? SyKit. ?]
为了扫除障碍， 我们往scikit中导入数据集。
We'll use Iris again, because it's handily included.
我们要再次用Iris， 它的数据已经包含其中 非常方便。
Now, we already saw Iris in episode two.
我们已经在第二集中见到过Iris。
But what we haven't seen before is
但我们之前没有见到的是
that I'm calling the features x and the labels y.
我将两个术语称作 特征x与标签y。
Why is that?
为什么呢？
Well, that's because one way to think of a classifier
这是因为看待分类器的一种方式
is as a function.
是看成一种函数。
At a high level, you can think of x as the input
在更高层面，你可以认为x是输入，
and y as the output.
y是输出。
I'll talk more about that in the second half of this episode.
我会在后半集进一步讲述这部分。
After we import the data set, the first thing we want to do
我们导入了数据集，第一步要做的
is partition it into Train and Test.
就是把它分成训练数据和测试数据。
And to do that, we can import a handy utility,
为此，我们可以导入一个方便的实体，
and it makes the syntax clear.
让句法更清晰。
We're taking our x's and our y's,
我们现在定义了我们的x和y，
or our features and labels, and partitioning them
特征和标签，然后把它们分开
into two sets.
成两个集合。
X_train and y_train are the features and labels
x_train和 y_train
And X_test and y_test are the features and labels
x_test 和y_test
Here, I'm just saying that I want half the data to be
这里，我要将一半的数据
used for testing.
用作测试。
So if we have 150 examples in Iris, 75 will be in Train
所以，在Iris中我们有150个样本，
Now we'll create our classifier.
现在我们要建立分类器。
I'll use two different types here
这里我要用两种类型
to show you how they accomplish the same task.
来向大家展示如何实现同一个任务。
Let's start with the decision tree we've already seen.
首先我们来用已经见过的决策树。
Note there's only two lines of code
请注意：这里有两行代码，
that are classifier-specific.
它们仅适用于分类器。
Now let's train the classifier using our training data.
现在让我们来用我们的训练集来训练分类器。
At this point, it's ready to be used to classify data.
到这里，它已经可以用来分类数据了。
And next, we'll call the predict method
然后，我们会调用预测方法
and use it to classify our testing data.
并用它来分类测试数据。
If you print out the predictions,
如果你打印出来预测结果，
you'll see there are a list of numbers.
就会发现有一串数字。
These correspond to the type of Iris
它们分别对应于Iris的类型，
the classifier predicts for each row in the testing data.
是分类器对测试数据每一行进行的预测。
Now let's see how accurate our classifier
现在让我们来看看我们的分类器
was on the testing set.
在测试集上的运行是否准确。
Recall that up top, we have the true labels for the testing
向前回顾，我们有测试数据的真实标签。
To calculate our accuracy, we can
为了计算准确性，
compare the predicted labels to the true labels,
我们可以将预测的标签与真实的标签比较
and tally up the score.
计算出得分。
There's a convenience method in [? Sykit ?]
对此，scikit中有个比较方便的方法
we can import to do that.
我们可以导入。
Notice here, our accuracy was over 90%.
看这里，我们的准确性超过90%。
If you try this on your own, it might be a little bit different
如果你自己尝试一遍，结果可能略有不同
because of some randomness in how the Train/Test
因为在训练/测试数据的划分上
data is partitioned.
存在一定的随机性。
Now, here's something interesting.
这是比较有趣的一点。
By replacing these two lines, we can use a different classifier
通过取代这两行，我们可以用另一种分类器
to accomplish the same task.
来完成相同的任务。
Instead of using a decision tree,
我们不使用决策树，
we'll use one called [? KNearestNeighbors. ?]
而是用一个叫KNearestNeighbors的程序
If we run our experiment, we'll see that the code
如果我们运行程序，
The accuracy may be different when you run it,
当你自己运行时结果可能有所不同，
because this classifier works a little bit differently
因为这个分类器工作方式略有不同
and because of the randomness in the Train/Test split.
还有划分训练/测试数据的随机性。
Likewise, if we wanted to use a more sophisticated classifier,
类似地，如果我们要用一种更加复杂的分类器，
we could just import it and change these two lines.
我们只需要导入它，然后改变这两行。
Otherwise, our code is the same.
与此同时，其他部分保持不变。
The takeaway here is that while there are many different types
另外要注意的是， 尽管有各种类型的分类器
of classifiers, at a high level, they have a similar interface.
在更高层次上， 它们拥有相似的接口。
Now let's talk a little bit more about what
现在我们深入讲述
it means to learn from data.
从数据中学习意味着什么。
Earlier, I said we called the features x and the labels y,
之前，我说过特征x与标签y，
because they were the input and output of a function.
它们是一个函数的输入和输出。
Now, of course, a function is something we already
当然，函数是一种
know from programming.
我们在编程中已经了解的东西。
def classify-- there's our function.
def classify--这就是函数。
As we already know in supervised learning,
正如我们在监督学习中了解的，
we don't want to write this ourselves.
我们并不想亲自去写上这些东西。
We want an algorithm to learn it from training data.
我们想要一个算法来从训练数据中学习。
So what does it mean to learn a function?
所以学习一个函数是什么意思呢？
Well, a function is just a mapping from input
函数仅仅是一种映射，
to output values.
从输入到输出值。
Here's a function you might have seen before-- y
这是一个函数，你之前可能看到过——
equals mx plus b.
y=mx+b。
That's the equation for a line, and there
这是一条直线的方程，
are two parameters-- m, which gives the slope;
有两个参数：m代表斜率，
and b, which gives the y-intercept.
b代表y轴截距。
Given these parameters, of course,
给定这些参数，
we can plot the function for different values of x.
我们就可以画出不同x值得函数值。
Now, in supervised learning, our classified function
现在，在监督学习下，我们的分类函数
might have some parameters as well,
也可能有一些参数，
but the input x are the features for an example we
但输入x是一个要分类样本的特征
So what could the body of the function look like?
那么函数主体是什么样的呢？
Well, that's the part we want to write algorithmically
这部分就是我们要写的算法，
or in other words, learn.
或者说，学习算法。
The important thing to understand here
在这里，我们需要理解的重要一点
is we're not starting from scratch
即我们并非从头开始
and pulling the body of the function out of thin air.
从无到有得到函数主体。
Instead, we start with a model.
相反，我们从模型开始。
And you can think of a model as the prototype for
你可以把模型当成一个原型
or the rules that define the body of our function.
用做定义我们函数主体的规则。
Typically, a model has parameters
一般的，一个模型具有参数，
that we can adjust with our training data.
参数根据训练数据作调整。
And here's a high-level example of how this process works.
关于这部分如何运行，来看这个高级的例子。
Let's look at a toy data set and think about what kind of model
我们来看一个玩具数据集，想想什么样的模型
we could use as a classifier.
可以用作分类器。
Pretend we're interested in distinguishing
假设我们想要区分
between red dots and green dots, some of which
红点和绿点，
To do that, we'll use just two features--
为此，我们需要用到两种特征
the x- and y-coordinates of a dot.
每个点的x轴和y轴坐标。
Now let's think about how we could classify this data.
现在考虑该如何区分这两种点。
We want a function that considers
我们需要一个函数，
a new dot it's never seen before,
当有一个新的没见过的点到来，
and classifies it as red or green.
可以区分它是红的还是绿的。
In fact, there might be a lot of data we want to classify.
事实上，我们可能有很多的数据想要分类。
Here, I've drawn our testing examples
这里我画了一些测试样本
in light green and light red.
用浅红色和浅绿色。
These are dots that weren't in our training data.
这些点并不存在于训练数据中。
The classifier has never seen them before, so how can
分类器也从没见过他们，
it predict the right label?
那它是怎么预测出正确的标签呢？
Well, imagine if we could somehow draw a line
想象我们可以以一种方式画一条线
across the data like this.
像这样穿过数据。
Then we could say the dots to the left
然后我们可以说
of the line are green and dots to the right of the line are
线左侧的是绿的，右侧的是红的。
And this line can serve as our classifier.
这条线可以当成一个分类器。
So how can we learn this line?
所以我们怎么学习这条线呢？
Well, one way is to use the training data to adjust
一个办法就是利用训练数据
the parameters of a model.
来调整模型的参数。
And let's say the model we use is a simple straight line
而且我们认为使用的模型是一条简单的直线
like we saw before.
如之前所示。
That means we have two parameters to adjust-- m and b.
也就是说我们有两个参数要调整：m和b。
And by changing them, we can change where the line appears.
通过改变它们，我们可以改变直线所在的位置。
So how could we learn the right parameters?
那么我们如何学习得到正确的参数呢？
Well, one idea is that we can iteratively adjust
一个想法是通过迭代
them using our training data.
利用训练数据来调整得到。
For example, we might start with a random line
比如，初始时我们用一条随机的直线，
and use it to classify the first training example.
然后用它来分类第一个训练数据。
If it gets it right, we don't need to change our line,
如果是正确的，就不用改变直线，
so we move on to the next one.
接着分类下一个训练数据。
But on the other hand, if it gets it wrong,
而相反，如果出错，
we could slightly adjust the parameters of our model
我们可以轻微地改变模型的参数
to make it more accurate.
使之更准确。
The takeaway here is this.
这一点需格外注意。
One way to think of learning is using training data
看待学习的一种方式
Now, here's something really special.
这里是非常特殊的一点，
It's called tensorflow/playground.
称为TensorFlow游戏场。
This is a beautiful example of a neural network
这是神经网络的一个优美范例，
you can run and experiment with right in your browser.
你可以直接在浏览器上运行与实验。
Now, this deserves its own episode for sure,
这部分值得安排单独的一集，
but for now, go ahead and play with it.
但现在就可以去体验一下它。
It's awesome.
非常赞。
The playground comes with different data
游乐场自带了不同的数据集
sets you can try out.
供你来尝试。
Some are very simple.
有一些非常简单。
For example, we could use our line to classify this one.
例如，我们可以用直线来区分这个。
Some data sets are much more complex.
有一些数据相当复杂。
This data set is especially hard.
这个数据集非常难。
And see if you can build a network to classify it.
来看看你是否可以建立一个网络来区分它。
Now, you can think of a neural network
现在你可以考虑一个神经网络
as a more sophisticated type of classifier,
当作一个复杂的分类器，
like a decision tree or a simple line.
像决策树或简单直线。
But in principle, the idea is similar.
但理论上，思想是相似的。
OK.
好的。希望对大家有用。
I just created a Twitter that you can follow
我刚创建了一个推特账号大家可以关注
to be notified of new episodes.
来接收新一集的更新提示。
And the next one should be out in a couple of weeks,
下一集将在几周后更新，
depending on how much work I'm doing for Google I/O. Thanks,
取决于我在谷歌I/O上的工作量。